Wilmar A. Stephens

25 West 132nd Street, Apartment 6M New York, NY 10037

Phone: (212) 353-1241 e-mail: wilmars@alumni.brown.edu

Summary

Technology professional with over twenty years of experience working in diverse environments including Windows, Linux, Active Directory, AWS, VMware, Azure, ServiceNow, SQL Server, and Office365

- Implement infrastructure as code using Terraform
- Configuration management and automation with Ansible
- Manage products and services in AWS
- Build and maintain Jenkins controllers, nodes, and pipelines
- Maintain Git repositories in Bitbucket

Technical Skills

Operating Systems

Windows, UNIX, Linux, MacOs

Languages

PowerShell, Python, JavaScript, PERL, C, bash shell scripting

Protocols

Active Directory, LDAP, DHCP, SAN/NAS, HTTP, ssh

AWS

S3, Cloudfront, Route53, EC2, ECS, Lambda, DynamoDB

Software

Terraform, Ansible, Packer Jira, Confluence, SQL Server, , VMware vCenter, IIS,

Certification

ITIL Foundation

Experience

Equinox New York, NY 2017-present

DevOps Engineer

- Enforce, maintain, and improve systems engineering and DevOps best practices.
- Implement infrastructure as code using Terraform.
- Create Ansible Roles and Playbooks for configuration management.
- Create Packer configurations for immutable infrastructure.
- Build Jenkins Pipelines.
- Build, support, and maintain cloud infrastructure in AWS.
- Manage SAML integrations.
- Set up and manage two-factor authentication solutions.
- Monitor systems with NewRelic.
- Participate in on-call rotation.

Outbrain, Inc. New York, NY 2014-2017

IT Manager

- Manage and grow a team of IT Engineers/System Administrators in the Outbrain NYC office that provides support for US and Brazil offices.
- Train and develop members of the global IT team.
- Work with the global IT team to implement consistent standards, automate common procedures, and ensure high levels of security and availability.
- Implement and support IT server, voice/video, and network resources.

- Coordinate the implementation of ServiceNow to provide global ITSM solution.
- Function as lead system administrator for ServiceNow.
- Build, configure, and maintain virtual servers in a VMware vSphere and AWS environments.
- Maintain users and groups in OpenLDAP.
- Evaluate business requirements and design IT solutions to fulfill them.
- Manage relationships with software, hardware, and service vendors.
- Plan and design disaster recovery plan.
- Assist the Director of IT with budget planning and tracking.
- Build custom applications and integrations in ServiceNow for Business Intelligence and Information Systems team.
- Develop integrations between ServiceNow and other solutions including JAMF Casper, Dell Kace, OpenLDAP, and Jira.
- Work with security and compliance teams to implement controls and checks in the IT environment.
- Manage the IT portion of office renovation and relocation activities.

ideeli, Inc. New York, NY 2011-2014

Windows System Engineer

- Build, configure, and maintain Windows servers for Epicor ERP software in multiple environments.
- Create custom monitoring for Epicor ERP software.
- Document policies and procedures for Epicor ERP software.
- Serve as primary contact for vendor support of Epicor ERP software.
- Maintain users and groups for Epicor ERP software.
- Build and monitor SQL Servers.
- Server as lead systems engineer for building and configuring ERP integrated third-party PO management software.
- Write Powershell scripts to diagnose and address issues related to ERP software.
- Build daily report in Powershell to monitor PO activity in PO management software
- Coordinate the migration of ERP software and servers between data centers.
- Participate in 24X7 on-call rotation for systems engineering group.
- Trougleshoot issues that trigger on-call alerts for Linux and Windows servers.
- Build VMware vCenter virtualized server environment for corporate environment.
- Build, configure, and maintain VMware virtual servers for corporate environment.
- Setup Nagios monitoring of corporate environment.
- Provide third level support for corporate IT issues.
- Build, configure and maintain NAS device for photo studio.
- Build Active Directory 2008 domain for software regression testing.
- Maintain users, groups, servers and, workstations in Active directory.

Juno Online Services, Inc. New York, NY 1997 - 2011

LAN Administrator (2002 – 2011)

- Build and maintain VMware vSphere environment to replace physical servers.
- Plan Exchange Server 2010 deployment including coordinating with other

- corporate entities and documenting progress.
- Monitor and support Windows DNS infrastructure and maintain interoperability with UNIX DNS servers.
- Coordinate the integration of messaging, DNS, and Active Directory around the mergers and acquisitions of business units.
- Assist with the planning and support of Windows servers and Network Appliance storage systems in Los Angles office.
- Build, configure, and maintain Network Appliance iSCSI based SAN for Exchange server 2003 storage.
- Build Windows domain controllers, Exchange Servers, and application servers including security patches, software and hardware upgrades, and consolidations.
- Administer Windows and UNIX user accounts, group membership, DNS, Active Directory, and SMTP using GUI and command line utilities.
- Install, configure, and oversee Exchange 5.5 and 2003 servers including upgrade from Exchange 5.5 to 2003.
- Manage network monitoring of Windows and UNIX servers.
- Integrate Active Directory and Exchange with new business entities resulting from mergers and acquisitions.
- Provide UNIX server support.
- Troubleshoot corporate mail flow on Sendmail, qmail, MailMarshal, and Exchange systems..
- Integrate UNIX and Windows systems using Samba.

Manager System Services/NT Administrator (2000 – 2002)

- Managed two Help Desk Associates.
- Trained five members of the Help Desk team on Windows NT and UNIX systems.
- Implemented and maintained network monitoring of Windows systems using SNMP.
- Evaluated hardware and software solutions for the office environment.
- Maintained remote access solutions including PPP, ISDN, and VPN.
- Provided UNIX (Solaris) server support, including jumpstart installs and software distribution.

•

Help Desk Associate (1997 – 2000)

- Resolved hardware and software issues.
- Built and configured Windows NT Servers
- Created and maintained Windows NT and UNIX accounts for office users.
- Participated in on-duty rotation.

Education

Brown University, Providence, RI Sc.B. Biochemistry

1993 - 1997